MATTHIEU OLEKHNOVITCH

STUDENT AT ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE

CONTACT

+33 6 95 67 09 46

matthieu.olekhnovitch@polytechnique.edu www.linkedin.com/in/matthieu-olekhnovitch



www.github.com/Matt-Olek



Paris, France

SKILLS

- Python Java JS C++
- Pytorch Keras Sklearn
- Dev Web (React, Django, php)
- SQL, Redis, DataBricks

LANGUAGES

French - Native

English - C1 or above (107/120 TOEFL)

German - B2 Russian - A2

PROJECTS

LLM HACK - Paris 2024

Developped an autonomous agent that can explore the web to find accurate data, pack it and serve it with a personalized API. Worked with tutors from Mistral AI and HuggingFace

LLM HACK - Paris 2024

Developped an autonomous agent that can explore the web to find accurate data, pack it and serve it with a personalized API. Worked with tutors from Mistral AI and HuggingFace

Digital Services (h)Acked -Brussels 2024

Developped a RAG architecture based on LLMs to serve API documentation from scrapped data. Computed researches on french HPC 'Jean Zay'

IPPMED Hackathon - Lung Cancer detection - 2023

Team research project on computer vision. Developed and trained deep learning models for tumor cells detection. Computation realised on Telecom Paris supercomputer (3.5Pflops/s)

EDUCATION

ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE (PALAISEAU, FRANCE)

Diplôme d'ingénieur (Master of Advanced engineering)

Majoring in Computer Science - GPA 3.53/4

Coursework include: Foundations of Machine learning, Machine and Deep Learning, Database Management Systems, Data Visualization

LYCEE PASTEUR (NEUILLY, FRANCE)

CPGE - Preparatory classes

2019 - 2021

Majoring in Advanced Engineering and Science - GPA 4.0/4

Coursework include: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science

LYCEE NOTRE DAME (BOULOGNE, FRANCE)

Baccalauréat, High School Diploma with High Honours

2016 - 2019

Coursework include: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF LUXEMBOURG (LUXEMBOURG)

Al Research Intern - Securiy and Trust - SERVAL Team

Apr. 2024 - Sep. 2024

Specialized in Reinforcement Learning techniques to enhance time series classification and forecasting metrics. Developed an advanced iteration of the AutoAugment algorithm for large-scale data augmentation based on mathematical optimization.

WORLDLINE (LYON, FRANCE)

Al Researcher Intern - LABS Department

Jun. 2023 - Sep. 2023

Spearheaded research on Al-driven code reviewing for proactive issueforecasting in large-scale programming projects. Devised and executed comprehensive analysis processes to optimize project outcomes and data retrieval.

BRIGADE DE SAPEURS-POMPIERS DE PARIS

Battalion Chief - Paris-13 Fire Department

Oct. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Commanded emergency operations as a French army officer, leading teams of up to 15 personnel. Thrived in high-pressure environments, managing and aiding victims during critical emergencies.

REWARDS

Excellence Scolarship

2019 - 2021 - Delivered by the french Ministry of Education

International Chemistry Olympiads

2020 - Ranked 8th in France

France Defence ministry bronze medal

2022 - Delivered by the french army ministry by way of exception

Outstanding investment award

2023 - Delivered by EcolePolytechnique for the investment in the associative life